Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores, 1828-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Program and thematic groupings, circa 1840-1993, VII.; Folder 1063-Folder 1218
  - Hollywood elegies, 1919-1992, VII.D; Folder 1112-Folder 1129
    - Hollaender, Friedrich Foreign affair. Illusions, 1948, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Chappell Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. Includes 1 ink manuscript leaf with parts of the melody written out. (Box 48, Folder 1114)
    - Hollaender, Friedrich Mady - Foxtrot, 1919, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Adolph Fürstner Instrumentation: For voice and piano Marked with duration and some translations of the German text. (Box 48, Folder 1115)
    - Hollaender, Friedrich Man about town. Strange enchantment, 1939, 1 score (1 leaf); Print (photocopy) Famous Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. Contains only the melody line with words and chord symbols. (Box 48, Folder 1116)
    - Hollaender, Friedrich Mélodie perverse. Valse Boston, 1919, 1 score (5 leaves); Print (photocopy) Adolph Fürstner Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1117)
    - Kaper, Bronislaw, 1902-1983 Lili. Hi-lili, Hi-lo, 1952, 1 score (5 leaves); Print (photocopy) Robbins Music Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1118)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951 Brettl-Lieder. Colly, 1970, 1 score (7 leaves); Print (photocopy) Belmont Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains some performance markings. (Box 48, Folder 1119)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951 Deutsche Volkslied. Selections, 1958, 1 score (7 leaves); Print (photocopy) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1120)
      Der Mai tritt ein mit Freuden -- Es gingen zwei Gespielen gut -- Mein Herz ist mir gemenget -- Mein Herz in steten Treuen.
    - Steiner, Max, 1888-1971 Gone with the wind. Ashley and Melanie, 1940, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Warner Brothers Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1121)
    - Waxman, Franz, 1906-1967 Place in the sun, 1951, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Paramount Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1122)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Abschiedsbrief, 1981, 1 score (6 leaves); Print (photocopy) European American Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano English translation written onto score. (Box 48, Folder 1123)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Complainte de la Seine, 1934, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Editions Coda Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1124)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Dreigroschenoper. Moritat von Mackie Messer, undated, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Campbell Connelly & Co. Instrumentation: For voice and piano German translation of French text written onto score. (Box 48, Folder 1125)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Je ne t'aime pas, undated, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1126)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Lady in the dark. My ship, 1969, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Hampshire House Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1127)
    - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Youkali. Tango habanera, undated, 1 score (4 leaves); Print (photocopy) Heugel Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 48, Folder 1128)
    - Hollywood elegies notes, 1992?, 10 leaves; Contains program for program titled Hollywood elegies, or Thomas Mann's Hollywood (elsewhere titled From Berlin to Hollywood, or the Hollywood elegies), Mikhashoff's biographical notes about composers on the program, and some alternate program orders. (Box 48, Folder 1129)
  - Melodeclamation, circa 1840-1977, VII.E; Folder 1130-Folder 1186
    Contains scores used or considered for Mikhashoff's concert programs dedicated to works written in the tradition of melodeclamation.
    - Albeniz, Isaac, 1860-1909 Rimas de Becquer. No. 4, undated, 1 score (1 leaf); Print (photocopy) Unión Musical Española Instrumentation: For narrator and piano English translation of spoken text added. Additional name: Bécquer, Gustavo Adolfo, 1836-1870 (Box 48, Folder 1130)
    - Attinello, Paul Gregory Song for speaker, flute, and four stringed instruments, 1976, 1 score (4 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker, flute, 4 stringed instruments Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1131)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 Egmont, undated, 3 scores; Manuscript and print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For narrator and piano Marked with durations. Additional name: Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1941-1993 (Box 48, Folder 1132)
      Ink manuscript version of Mikhashoff's transcription for voice and piano with typewritten English translation attached -- Photocopy of manuscript of Mikhashoff's transcription for voice and piano with additional manuscript and printed music -- Photocopy of printed edition of same passage, No. 8, for narrator and string quintet.
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 Klage, undated, 1 score (1 leaf); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice Not marked. Melody from the Adagio movement of Beethoven's Piano sonata op. 2 no. 1 with German words set to it. Melody line only. (Box 48, Folder 1133)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 König Stephan. Selections, undated, 1 score (20 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and orchestra Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1134)
    - Bergh, Arthur, 1882-1962 Raven, op. 2, 1910, 1 score (13 leaves); Print (photocopy) Wa-Wan Press Instrumentation: For narrator and piano Not marked. Pages 175-198 on 13 leaves (folded). (Box 48, Folder 1135)
    - Castérède, Jacques, 1926-2014 Trois fanfares pour des proclamations de Napoleon, 1954, 1 score (35 pages) and 8 parts; Print Alphonse Leduc Instrumentation: For narrator and, brass and percussion Not marked. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 48, Folder 1136)
    - Charpentier, Marc-Antoine, 1643-1704 Polichinelle. Selections, 1925, 1 score (5 leaves); Print (photocopy) Heugel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Not marked. "Premier intermède du Malade imaginaire de Molière. Reconstructed and completed by Julien Tiersot. Additional name: Tiersot, Julien, 1857-1936 (Box 48, Folder 1137)
    - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918 Six epigraphes antiques, 1915, 1 score (30 leaves); Print (photocopy) A. Durand Instrumentation: For speaker and two pianos Contains some performance markings. Typescript English translation attached to score. Includes typescript English translation (Box 48, Folder 1138)
      Pour invoquer Pan, dieu du vent d'ête? -- Pour un tombeau sans nom -- Pour que la nuit soit propice -- Pour la danseuse aux crotales -- Pour l'Egyptienne -- Pour remercier la pluie au matin.
    - Dvorák, Antonín, 1841-1904 Josef Kajetán tyl, 1951, 1 score (35 pages); Print Orbis Instrumentation: For speakers and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1139)
    - Dworkin, Seth Howard Dathan, 1973?, 1 score (11 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Not marked Also includes 9 leaves of photocopied manuscript performance instruction. (Box 48, Folder 1140)
    - Fibich, Zdenek, 1850-1900 Four concert melodramas, undated, 4 scores; Print (photocopy) A. Urbanek Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Pomsta kvetin includes a handwritten English translation on the score. (Box 48, Folder 1141)
      Štedrý den-- Pomsta kvetin -- Vecnost -- Hakon.
    - Gilman, Lawrence, 1878-1939 Curlew, 1904, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Wa-Wan Press Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Marked with duration. (Box 48, Folder 1142)
    - Gilman, Lawrence, 1878-1939 Dream of death, 1903, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Wa-Wan Press Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Marked with duration. (Box 48, Folder 1143)
    - Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907 Bergliot, 1953, 1 score (23 pages); Print C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Not marked. (Box 48, Folder 1144)
    - Golybina, Svetlana Edge of sound, undated, 1 score (10 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Poetry by Alexei Kruchonykh; translated into English by Paul Schmidt. Additional name: Schmidt, Paul, 1934-1999 (Box 48, Folder 1145)
    - Hardyk, Joel M. I never saw another butterfly, 1976, 2 scores (6 leaves each); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For soprano, alto, and oboe. Not marked. Movements 1 and 5 of I never saw another butterfly, settings of poems by children of the Holocaust. (Box 49, Folder 1146)
      At Terezin -- The butterfly.
    - Hawley, Stanley, 1867-1916 Dramatic poems. Selections, 1904, 3 scores; Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Not marked. (Box 49, Folder 1147)
      No. 2: The black heart -- No. 4: The sisters -- No. 9: The white moth.
    - Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963 Herodiade, 1955, 1 score (22 leaves); Print (photocopy) Schott Instrumentation: For speaker and orchestra; piano reduction Speaker's French text written onto score throughout. Text by Mallarmé. Additional name: Mallarmé, Stéphane, 1842-1898 (Box 49, Folder 1148)
    - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955 Amphion. Selections, 1931, 1 score (12 leaves); Print (photocopy) Rouart, Lerolle & Cie. Instrumentation: Vocal score; originally for speaker, baritone, 4 female voices, choir, and orchestra Contains some performance markings. Incomplete: pages 33- 41, 55-57. (Box 49, Folder 1149)
    - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955 Miracle de Notre-Dame. Selections, 1926, 1 score (8 leaves); Print (photocopy) Editions Maurice Senart Instrumentation: Reduction for speaker and piano Not marked. Not marked. Incomplete: pages 1-8. Piano reduction by A. Vaurabourg. Alternate title: Impératrice aux rochers. (Box 49, Folder 1150)
    - Horvath, Josef Maria, 1931- Blinde, 1962, 1 score (24 pages); Print Henry Litolff's Verlag/ C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For mezzo-soprano, 2 speakers, and flute, trumpet, cello, and piano Not marked. (Box 49, Folder 1151)
    - Jemelik, Antonín Tri melodramy, 1972, 1 score (8 pages); Print Panton Instrumentation: For speaker and piano English translation written onto score for 3rd movement. (Box 49, Folder 1152)
      Belounka holubicka -- Pohadka -- Podzimni pisen.
    - Leroux, Xavier, 1863-1919 Musique pour de scène pour Cléopâtre. Selections, 1891, 1 score (9 leaves); Print (photocopy) G. Hartmann Instrumentation: Reduction for speaker and piano. Typescript text attached between staves on pages 91-93 Incomplete: pages 37-41 and 91-93. (Box 49, Folder 1153)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Blinde Sänger, 1936, 1 score (13 leaves); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf und Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Typescript English translation attached to score throughout. (Box 49, Folder 1154)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Helges treue, 1874, 1 score (12 leaves); Print (photocopy) J. Schuberth & Co. Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Not marked. "Ballade von Strachwitz componirt von Felix Dräseke". Additional name: Draeseke, Felix, 1835-1913 (Box 49, Folder 1155)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Lenore, undated, 2 scores (15 leaves each); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano One copy marked for performance, including the replacement of the original German text with an English translation. (Box 49, Folder 1156)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Toten Dichters Liebe, undated, 2 scores (11 leaves each); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Both copies marked for performance, including the replacement of the original German text with an English translation. (Box 49, Folder 1157)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Traurige Mönch, undated, 3 scores (5 leaves each); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Two copies marked for performance, including the replacement of the original German text with an English translation. (Box 49, Folder 1158)
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Zwei Vortragsstücke, 1890, 1 score (8 leaves); Print (photocopy) C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung Instrumentation: For organ; prepared here for speaker and piano The Trauerode has an added typescript French text added throughout. (Box 49, Folder 1159)
      Introitus -- Trauerode.
    - Loomis, Harvey Worthington, 1865-1930 In the moon-shower, op. 70, no. 4, 1902, 2 scores (4 leaves each); Print (photocopy) Wa-Wan Press Instrumentation: For speaker, soprano or tenor, violin, and piano Both copies marked for performance, including bowings. (Box 49, Folder 1160)
    - Lully, Jean Baptiste, 1632-1687 Plaisirs de l'ile enchantee. Deuxième journée la Princesse d'Elide. Selections, undated, 1 score (27 leaves); Print (photocopy) Editions de la Revue Musicale Instrumentation: For singers, instrumental ensemble, and continuo Contains small number of performance markings. Incomplete: pages 15-33 and 39-46. (Box 49, Folder 1161)
    - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 Erinnyes. Selections, undated, 1 score (21 leaves); Print (photocopy) Heugel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano There are 3 copies of number 8, 2 of which are marked, one with an English translation. Incomplete: numbers 5, 6, 8, 9, and 10. (Box 49, Folder 1162)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 Zaide. Gematz allein, undated, 2 scores (6 pages each); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: Vocal score for speaker and piano Both copies contain an English translation and some performance markings. Includes 2 typescript leaves of English text. (Box 49, Folder 1163)
    - Newell, John, 1949- Sonnet for speaker and piano, 1976, 1 score (22 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Contains performance markings. Text by William Shakespeare. (Box 49, Folder 1164)
    - Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 Contes d'Hoffmann. Selections, 1959, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) G. Schirmer Instrumentation: Vocal score for speaker and piano Not marked. "Alternate ending" - pages 313-314. (Box 49, Folder 1165)
    - Perrachio, Luigi, 1883-1966 Luna, 1925, 1 score (29 pages); Print G. Ricordi Instrumentation: For piano 4-hands Not marked. (Box 49, Folder 1166)
    - Pierné, Gabriel, 1863-1937 Yanthis. Selections, undated, 5 scores; Print (photocopy) and Manuscript Instrumentation: For speaker and piano, and violin and piano One copy of Lamento includes English translation; both copies of the manuscript edition of Mikhashoff's version for violin and piano are marked for performance. (Box 49, Folder 1167)
      Two photocopies of print edition of Lamento -- One manuscript and one photocopy of Mikhashoff's version for violin and piano -- Photocopy of print edition of Pierné's work Chanson parlee (1 leaf)
    - Reinecke, Carl, 1824-1910 Melodramen, op. 111. Selections, 1908, 1 score (15 leaves); Print (photocopy) Fr. Kistner Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Contains small number of performance markings. (Box 49, Folder 1168)
      No. 2: Schelm von Bergen -- No. 4: Schön Astrid.
    - Rohmer, Sax, 1883-1959 Orange blossom, 1921, 1 score (6 leaves); Print (photocopy) Reynolds & Co. Instrumentation: For speaker and voice Not marked. (Box 49, Folder 1169)
    - Rothstein, Joseph Lines, circa 1974, 1 score (15 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Contains performance markings. Title from title of poem by Rimbaud with first line in English: When the world comes down to this one dark wood. (Box 49, Folder 1170)
    - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 Abschied von der Erde, D. 829, undated, 2 scores (2 leaves each); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano English translation written throughout on one copy; changes to piano part indicated on other copy. (Box 49, Folder 1171)
    - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 Winterreise. Selections; arranged, circa 1840, 1 score (20 leaves); Print (photocopy) Tobias Haslinger Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. Erstarrung -- Der Lindenbaum -- Wasserfluth -- Die Post -- Muth -- Der Leyermann. Additional name: Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 (Box 49, Folder 1172)
    - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 Zauberharfe. Selections, undated, 1 score (9 leaves); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and orchestra Not marked. (Box 49, Folder 1173)
      No. 8: Melodram -- No. 11: Melodram hinter den Coulissen.
    - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Ballades, narrator, piano, op. 122, undated, 1 score (10 leaves); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano English translation typed onto score of No. 2 with indications for when text should be spoken. (Box 49, Folder 1174)
      Ballade vom Haideknaben -- Die Flüchtlinge.
    - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Schöne Hedwig, undated, 1 score (5 leaves); Print (photocopy) Breitkopf & Härtel Instrumentation: For speaker and piano English translation typed onto score with additional indications for when text should be spoken. (Box 49, Folder 1175)
    - Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957 Melodram Ettensamt skidspår, 1934, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) A/B Nordiska Musikförlaget Instrumentation: For speaker and piano English translation written on score throughout. (Box 49, Folder 1176)
    - Skop, V. F. (Vaclav Felix), 1850-1932 Columbus, undated, 1 score (8 leaves); Print (photocopy) E. Jul. Pickenhahn Instrumentation: For speaker and piano (Box 49, Folder 1177)
    - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949 Enoch Arden, 1898, 2 scores (23 leaves each); Print (photocopy) R. Forberg Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Both copies marked for performance. (Box 49, Folder 1178)
    - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949 Schloss am Meere, 1911, 1 score (7 leaves); Print (photocopy) Adolph Fürstner Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Alternate English translation written onto the score throughout. (Box 49, Folder 1179)
    - Suk, Josef, 1874-1935 Radúz a Mahulena. Selections; arranged, undated, 1 score (19 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker, violin, and 2 pianos Contains performance markings. Incomplete? (Box 50, Folder 1180)
    - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 Pesn Zemfiry, undated, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains one comment about text. (Box 50, Folder 1181)
    - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 Kompositionen zu Goethes Faust, undated, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Contains some performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1182)
    - Unknown Setting of The Fire sermon from T. S. Eliot's The Waste Land, Part III, 1977, 1 score (31 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker, mezzo-soprano, clarinet, violin, cello, and piano (Box 50, Folder 1183)
    - Melodeclamation programs, notes, and clippings, 1972-1977, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 1184)
    - Melodeclamation correspondence, 1974-1976, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 1185)
    - Melodeclamation articles and notes, undated, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 1186)
  - Miss Jane's parlor, 1892-1993, VII.F; Folder 1187-Folder 1201
    Contains material for a concert program performed by soprano Jane Romanos and Yvar Mikhashoff.
    - Beach, H. H. A., Mrs., 1867-1944 Year's at the spring, 1900, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Arthur P. Schmidt Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. Op. 44 no. 1. Words by Robert Browning. (Box 50, Folder 1187)
    - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946 From the land of sky-blue water, 1909, 1 score (4 leaves); Print (photocopy) White-Smith Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Marked for performance including a brief summary of the song's content. (Box 50, Folder 1188)
    - Coleman, Emmet. G. Father, dear Father, come home, undated, 1 score (1 leaf); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1189)
    - Edwards, Gus, 1879-1945 I'm after Madame Tetrazzini's job, 1909, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Gus Edwards Music Instrumentation: For voice and piano Comments in caption about song's content. (Box 50, Folder 1190)
    - Edwards, Gus, 1879-1945 Pan, Pan, Pan, 1901, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Howely, Haviland & Dresser Instrumentation: For voice and piano Not marked. (Box 50, Folder 1191)
    - Gottschalk, Louis Moreau, 1829-1869 Last hope, 1856, 1884, 2 scores; Print Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 50, Folder 1192)
      Photocopy (11 leaves) of edition by Wm. Hall & Son -- Print copy of 1184 "New and only correct edition".
    - Harris, Chas. K. (Charles Kassell), 1864-1930 After the ball is over, 1892, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Chas. K. Harris Instrumentation: For voice and piano Score marked with cuts. (Box 50, Folder 1193)
    - Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 Fortune teller. Always do as people say you should, undated, 1 score (4 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1194)
    - Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 Fortune teller. Romany life, 1898, 1 score (7 leaves); Print (photocopy) M. Witmark & Sons Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1195)
    - Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 Mlle. Modiste. If I were on the stage, 1905, 1 score (8 leaves); Print (photocopy) M. Witmark & Sons Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains small number of performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1196)
    - Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 Naughty Marietta. Italian street song, 1921, 2 scores; Print M. Witmark & Sons Instrumentation: For voice and piano Photocopy marked with duration. Print copy in F major, photocopy in D major. (Box 50, Folder 1197)
    - Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951 Maytime. Will you remember, 1946, 1 score (5 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1198)
    - Stromberg, John, 1853-1902 Come down ma evenin' star, undated, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1199)
    - Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946 Bird in a gilded cage, 1900, 1 score (3 leaves); Print (photocopy) Shapiro Bernstein & Von Tilzer Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings. (Box 50, Folder 1200)
    - Miss Jane's parlor programs, 1991-1993, 2 programs; Instrumentation: For voice and piano For performances by soprano Jane Romanos and pianist Yvar Mikhashoff. (Box 50, Folder 1201)
      17 November 1991, Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Buffalo, New York -- 2 May 1993, Utrecht
  - Opera matinee, 1992, VII.G; Folder 1202-Folder 1204
    Contains scores used or considered for Mikhashoff's concert program titled Opera matinee.
    - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Années de pèlerinage, 2e année. Supplement. Canzone, undated, 1 score (5 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Based on Nessun maggior dolore from Rossini's Otello Additional name: Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 (Box 50, Folder 1202)
    - Vigeland, Nils Habanera from Jane Eyre, 1992, 1 score (4 leaves); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 50, Folder 1203)
    - Opera matinee program list and article, undated, 1 folder; Article from 4 July 1992 (Box 50, Folder 1204)
  - Vienna to New York, 1926-1993, VII.H; Folder 1205-Folder 1218
    Contains scores used or considered for Mikhashoff's concert program titled From Vienna to New York.
    - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Klavierstücke, op. 119. Intermezzo, 1974, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Wiener Urtext Edition Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. (Box 50, Folder 1205)
    - Cohen, Douglas, 1959- O Wort, 1992, 1 score (4 leaves); Print (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Not marked. Print from computer-notated score. "Hommage a Arnold Schoenberg." (Box 50, Folder 1206)